KEEP IN TOUCH:



615-852-8430



DYLAN@TEACH2.TECH



WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/DYLANIGRIFFITH



WWW.GITHUB.COM/DYLPICKLE11

PROFILE

Like many, I migrated to Music City to develop my skills as a musician- which culminated in my becoming a music professor and Community Director at Tennessee State University, a performer, and a composer of original music. While music is still a passion of mine, I found myself curious to create in a new medium after I saw a close friend make the career change to software development. She nudged me towards some introductory material and like a catchy tune, I was hooked. Coding unifies and satisfies my need for creativity, logic, and collaboration. What I love most is that I have the opportunity to take the smallest of elements and build intricate works that can help influence so many others.

PROJECTS SONGPLAN

A single page app that allows music educators to create, edit, save, and share their various song plans. This app digitizes and organizes educational songs for educators. It is a database with which music educators can consult resources freely and easily and share lessons plans with each other. Technologies used React, Javascript, BootStrap, ReactStrap, JSON, Postman Firebase. https://github.com/DylPickle11/MusicHQ-Capstone-App

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full-Stack Development. August 2019-Present

BELMONT UNIVERSITY

Masters of Music in Music Education. May 2012–May 2015

SPELMAN COLLEGE

Bachelor of Art in Music. August 2007-May 2011

Dylan Griffith

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Developer | Six-month full-stack bootcamp | August 2019 to Present

Built browser based full-stack application using:

- HTML, CSS/ Bootstrap, JavaScript, and React, C#, .Net, SQL
- · Components of agile software development
- · GitHub in group settings
- · Mapped data relationships using Entity Relationship Diagrams

Group Projects

Welcome to Nashville

Team-based project. A website that allows users to find things to do during a visit to Nashville. My roles included utilizing the Ticketmaster API to render data that gave concerts dates and times, render information to the DOM, save a personal itinerary for the client, and provide the CSS for the page. Languages utilized: HTML, CSS, vanilla JavaScript.

Nutstalgia/ NutShell React

Team-based project. Dashboard application that displays a users friends tasks, events, chats and news regarding their life. My roles included implemented storage session for a user, created news and event modules utilizing CRUD. Languages utilized: HTML, CSS, vanilla JavaScript, and React.

TrestleBridge

Team-based project. A command line application that allowed for the management of a fictional farm. My roles included creating methods for plant counting and choosing appropriate facilities. Languages utilized: C#.

Bangazon API/Bangazon WorkForce

Team-based project. Bangazon Workforce Management is an internal full stack application for human resources and IT departments. The application allows them to manage Employees, Training Programs, Departments, and Computers. My Roles included creating CRUD for Training Programs. Languages utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, SQL.

NSS HACKATHON

October 2019 | KewLyrics App | github.com/DylPickle11/KewLyrics-NSS-Hackathon

Created Music app that finishes lyrics of a forgotten song. Languages utilized HTML, CSS, vanilla JavaScript, and React.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

August 2016 to May 2019

Professor

- Designed and taught five classes: Music appreciation; Piano Proficiency I; Materials
 of Music; Materials of Music Lab; Music for Non-Majors.
- Developed personalized repertoire to meet individuals students' goals.
- · Developed and strengthened students technique and overall musicianship
- · Successfully prepared students for semester recitals
- Integrated musical learning application (Teoria) into the lab setting
- Utilized elearn (content, calendar, quizzes) for each class offering more access to tools and resources

Director of Community Academy Of Music and Arts (CAMA)

- Applied and obtained food grant for free breakfast and lunch for campers.
- Established an updated and effective website for the CAMA program
- Planned, created, and implemented online registration/utilizing Qualtrics and completed Procedural CAMA Handbook
- TSU Liaison and Coordinator for the Nashville Philharmonic Orchestra performance at TSU
- Developed, promoted and strengthened partnerships with outside entities such as intersection, MCYO, MNPS, Hadley Library to establish students to help within the community.

WARBY PARKER

OPA (Order Processing Associate) | July 2018 to May 2019

- Read pupillary distance for clients to ensure proper receipt of optical prescriptions
- Requested and faxed optical prescriptions
- Received, interpreted, confirmed, and transcribed clients optical prescriptions
- Completed high volumes of work under limited supervision
- · Provided wonderful customer service

NASHVILLE STATE COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Adjunct Faculty | January 2015 to August 2017

- Created and executed curriculum for class piano, music appreciation (Music Intro), and applied piano
- Developed and strengthened students technique, knowledge, and overall musicianship
- Developed personalized repertoire to meet individuals students' goals
- Utilized technology (more) to assist in student learning and outcomes

MUSIC INSTRUCTION

Mobile Music Academy | July 2013 August 2018 Concordia Arts Academy | June 2015 to June 2016 GreenBrier High School | July 2013 to July 2014 W.O Smith | June 2013 to June 2014

- Developed personalized repertoire to meet individuals students' goals.
- Developed and strengthened students technique and overall musicianship.
- Successfully prepared students for semester recitals
- Worked the summer band camps 2013-2014
- Instructed flute and percussion for band campAssisted with marching technique and general ensemble
- Created and led music and theory activities for studentsAssisted in conducting and leading instrumental ensembles and choir productionsSupervised and assembled students for field trips.

ADDITIONAL CODE EXPERIENCE

HACKTOBER October 2019 | Contributer

TAUGHT PRE-WORK SESSION January 2020 | NSS

VOLUNTEER

STRATEGIC COORDINATOR Choral Arts Link | August 2019 to present

MUSIC INSTRUCTOR Tennessee High Education Initiative | January 2016 to August 2018

MUSIC INSTRUCTOR FAM Music Camp| June 2015 to present